♪ Il... ♪
♪ ...lumination ♪
♪ Illumination ♪
♪ Illumination. ♪
Hyah! Hyah!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Uh...
Eh...
- Hey.
- Hey. Yoo-hoo.
Oh!
All right, everybody,
gather round.
This is our latest,
very special exhibit
where you'll learn all about
your favorite movies
- and actors.
- Wow. -Ooh.
Welcome to
The Magic of Hollywood!
Look at all this cool stuff. Oh.
Look up there. It's E.T.
Oh, and look at this one.
Keanu Reeves.
And you all know
George Lucas, right?
Oh, yes, he's great.
I'd really like to go home now.
Come on, only a few more weeks
left in the exhibit.
You can do it.
Can I at least have
my cell phone?
Oh, George, you're just gonna
use it to call for help.
Oh, and over here,
oh, wow, the most important
figures in the exhibit.
Without them,
there would be no Hollywood.
James and Henry!
Who?
Are you serious?
James and Henry.
- Minions.
- I know the Minions.
But I've never seen, uh...
James and Henry.
- Yeah. Never heard of them.
- Me neither.
This is insane!
James and Henry are legends, and
they changed Hollywood forever.
Not just Hollywood,
they changed the world.
And their story is epic.
They're what?
What is she talking about?
You know what? Change of plans.
Everybody, sit down. Now.
All of you. Come on, sit down.
Tommy. You, too, Glasses
and Mr. Johnson.
And-and-and you, too,
Bubble Girl.
As you may know,
throughout time,
dozens of Minion tribes
have been roaming our planet,
searching for
the perfect villain
to serve.
♪ Ho, ho... ♪
And among them
was a very special guy.
That's him right there.
James.
He liked to draw, paint,
but, above all,
he loved to invent stories
and share them with his buddies.
- Hey, Alberto. Look at me booka.
- Huh?
¿Te gusta?
Uh... um, meh.
Ah. Uh, Eric.
Huh?
Hey, James! Hey!
Okay?
Uh, uh, es... Sí, sí.
The rest of his tribe, however,
they were just interested
in one thing.
Big Boss. Ooh...
To serve the most evil
master they can find.
And this guy checked
all the boxes.
Scary? Check.
Burly? Check.
- Super mean?
- Ooh.
Pout! Pout! Pout!
Double check.
Oh.
No, no, no!
Pout! Pout! Pout!
He was a perfect ten.
To show their new master
how much they cared,
the Minions did everything
for him.
But James wanted
to go one step further
and create something
truly wonderful for his master.
Uh, uh, what? Ah.
Ah. Hey, Big Boss!
Hey, looka! Looka!
Regarde!
C'est tu!
Et c'est nous!
Big Boss! Big Boss! Big Boss!
Pout, pout, pout.
Uh...
No, pout, pout, pouta. No.
No.
Eh?
Regarde! Regarde!
Ah, ooh, ooh.
Uh, pulla, pulla...
Phew.
Hey, hey, uh, no, no, no!
¡Cuidado! ¡Cuidado!
Oomph!
Ow!
Oh! Ooh! Oh!
- Oh, James.
- James.
The Minions were banished
from the Cyclops's island
that day,
and everyone was mad at James.
James, James, James!
- Oh.
- Well, not everyone.
- One other Minion
found it very funny.
Big Boss. Pout, pout, pout.
Ayah, ouch.
And that was Henry.
Ooh la la la.
Allez.
Hey, James.
Ah, sí, sí.
Uh-uh.
Nope. Nope, nope, nope.
Hey.
Huh?
Mee-ta Henry.
Ah, bello. Mee-ta James.
- Tapioca?
- Ah, oh, tapioca.
Ooh, hey.
Sí.
Oh, oh.
Hey, oh!
- Ah, o-okay. Sí, sí.
- Sí. Sí.
Blah.
And from that moment on,
James and Henry
were inseparable.
The best of friends
and by each other's side
- no matter where they went...
- Big Boss! Big Boss!
- ...or who they worked for.
- Big Boss! Big Boss! Big Boss!
Their next master
was extremely promising,
very powerful and,
more importantly, very evil.
And his book-- ooh, dear me,
it had some wicked spells in it.
Misha stroganoff.
Oh la la la.
Brush up! Brush up!
No touch of la bookiski.
- No touch of!
- Okay, okay. No touch of.
Ah.
- No touch of!
- Bah no, no.
Hey, James. James.
Come here, come here. Looka.
Touch of la bookiski.
Oh.
Looka. Come here, come here.
Bella la monstra.
Ooh la. Ooh.
Oh, oh! La! La rabbit!
Holy kawaii! Voy a la spella.
Uh...
Aw.
...cute-a.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Uh, hah. Blah. Command-Zed.
Command-Zed!
Undo!
Once again, the Minions
had inadvertently lost a master.
Henry!
On the plus side,
James and Henry's friendship
became stronger that day...
- Uh...
...even if it made
some of the other Minions
unhappy.
Oh, this is Ed, by the way.
He's a friendly Minion
who is a bit hard of hearing.
So they came up with a way of
communicating with each other.
- Y polenta, la mango.
- Mm-hmm.
Come here.
Huh?
And so the Minions went
from one boss to the next.
And there were many.
The Big Boss!
Uh, buddies.
Por favor.
Uh. Huh? Ah!
Oh, Chris!
Oh, Bill.
Oh, Patrick.
Huh?
Oh, Brian.
But after a while,
they couldn't find
any more evil masters to serve.
For a very long time,
the Minions wandered about,
tired and losing hope.
Okay.
Okay?
And that
very bossy Minion there,
that's Dick.
He barked at everyone
to make camp for the night.
Eh, bup, bup, bup, bup, bup.
Now, because of their nonstop
blabbering and giggling,
Dick ordered Henry and James
to go sleep away from
everyone else, as per usual.
Which was fine with them,
as it meant they could
stay up all night
discussing the meaning of life,
the cosmos,
their hopes, their dreams.
Ooh la la. (speaks
Minionese) -JAMES: Bank you.
- Bellissimo, James.
- Uh-huh.
Ah. ...Dick.
...asparagus.
Mick or no.
Mick or no. Mick or no.
- DICK: Hey, yo!
Henry, James! Sleepa!
Hey.
Go, go, go.
- Hey, Henry, wake up.
- Huh?
Oof. And with that,
Dick lost his temper... again.
And he said all he had on
his mind about the two friends.
Henry thought long and hard
about Dick's remarks...
and decided to punch him.
But thankfully Ed intervened,
signed for his friend
to calm down,
breathe deeply...
- and...
- Hey. Hey!
...punched Dick himself.
Uh, putt, putt, putt, putt.
Okay?
Well, this seemed like
- the breaking point...
- Looka!
...but then Dick saw something
that would change
the Minions' lives forever.
Big Boss! Ah! Ooh! Ah!
♪ ♪
Big Boss.
Hey, buddies!
Bye-bye!
What the...?
Hyah!
Huh? Buddies, looka!
To the train!
- Follow him!
- Get on up! Get after him!
Go, go, go!
Hmm?
- After him!
- Come here, you little...
Hey!
Huh? Oh.
Hey! Down here!
Buddies! Helpa me!
What? Oh!
Whoa, whoa!
Big Boss! Hey!
- Uh, oh.
- Oh.
Hey, hey, looka.
Toot, toot!
Uh, uh, oh.
Oh, oh, oh.
Hey. Toot, toot!
- Toot!
- Agh.
- Broke off.
- Huh?
Toot, toot!
- Toot, toot, toot!
- Toot, toot!
Buddies, go, go!
Toot, toot!
Ah!
Please don't hurt me!
MINIONS
Big Boss.
Phew.
Look out!
Kumquat?
Huh?
No.
Stop!
Sto...
...op!
Toot, toot.
Cut!
Okay, people, back to one.
And you!
Do you have any idea
what you have done?
...la Boss y, uh, conducto...
Huh? E la toot, toot.
Y la James también.
Sí, toot, toot.
Stop! Stop.
You've ruined everything.
It was a perfect scene.
All that work. All that money.
All that effort.
Uh... No?
Get out of here.
You, you, you, you,
you, you, you, you.
- And you.
- Me?
Definitely you. Get out!
Out! Out, out, out, out, out!
Out!
Verschwindet!
Let's go again.
Uh, hey, boss.
We're out of film.
This is not going
to go down well.
You tell that no-talent bum
if he messes up again,
he's fired!
And then send him
a bottle of champagne
because it's his birthday.
Oh! There he is.
Our favorite director.
Hello, Mr. Bright.
- Mr. Bright.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- All right,
let's see what you shot.
Roll the scene, now.
We are so excited to see it.
Come on, let's go.
Just so you know, Mr. Bright,
we had...
a small problem.
A problem?
Is just a puzzle
for friends to solve.
Problems cost money, Elwood.
If this scene is terrible,
you will never work
in this town again.
But we're sure you'll do great
in any number of other towns.
Roll the scene, please,
and thank you.
Ooh, here we go.
What is going on?
I know. That's what I was
trying to tell you at the...
What are those things?
Uh... they, uh...
You changed the whole scene.
But I didn't.
I... oh, boy, I didn't.
It's genius!
What?
The scene, it's great.
It's better than great.
I love it!
Those sickly children,
oh, they're fantastic.
They have to be in
every shot of the movie.
Uh... yeah.
Okay. Absolutely.
I'm going to get
my very good friends--
just those, uh, uh,
what's their names--
and put them in the movie!
Sam?
Elwood?
Would you mind playing it?
All right.
Ah, that's the stuff, Frankie.
Ah, yes, it is, Elwood.
Schnell! Schnell! Get me my car!
Faster, faster!
We need to find them.
Where are they?
Get out of the way!
Move it, move it!
SUFFRAGETTES
Give women the vote!
- Give women the vote!
- Take the next right.
They could be on Sunset.
- Ah.
Oh, looka!
Ooh, ooh, ooh!
Mmm!
Hey, hey!
Oh.
Eh, looka.
Hey!
- Huh?
- Don't let 'em get away!
Huh?
Whoa!
My boys!
I've been looking all over
for you. Get in, get in.
- There they are!
- Uh...
Get those little guys!
Quick, quick.
Go, go, go!
Don't let them get away!
Banana!
Wunderbar. Wunderbar.
Uh, first things first.
Who are you?
- ...Henry.
- Y James.
...Dick.
- ...Ed.
- Uh...
- Soy Peter!
- ...Ken.
Is-is there a name
I can just call all of you?
Bah...
Minions.
Look, Minions, my name is Max.
Bello, Max!
Yeah, hi.
Okay, I'm so sorry
about earlier.
So, I would like
to work with you.
We should make movies.
- Movies?
- Huh?
You don't know what movies are?
Mm...
Movies are stories that
play out right in front of you,
and people love them and people
love the people who make them.
...storya.
James...
La storya.
Le movies? ¿Para mí?
Sí, James. Sí!
Welcome to
Bright Brothers Pictures,
where we make
all kinds of movies.
Oh, oh!
- Hello, Josh.
- Hey, Sam.
Perfect.
All right, positions, everybody!
Find your mark...
Whoo!
It's a wrap.
Congratulations, everyone!
Fantástico!
It is fantástico.
It's exciting, isn't it?
Oh!
Ah, James,
I love your enthusiasm.
How about you gentlemen?
Do you want to make movies,
too? -
Eh, buh, buh, buh, buh.
No maka le movies.
...Big Boss.
Mm. -Uh...
Le movies!
Excellent. Let's get to work.
So, I need you to act
in a, mm, very simple scene.
Here. You stay here,
and I shall return.
Uh...
Oh.
Okay, listen up.
So here's the scene.
You see those large,
heavily armed men?
They suspect you have killed
their leader,
and they want you dead.
Gweek.
Uh, gweek?
All right, I need you
to really sell the drama.
You do a good job,
and you're hired!
You fail, it's back
to wandering the streets,
scavenging for food.
Have fun with it!
Okay!
Ready, action!
Attack!
Uh, buddies?
No, no, no, no, no!
Henry!
Henry, helpa!
Buddies!
Help!
- Skoal!
Hey.
Cut!
Huh?
Okay, that was...
perfect!
Minions, are you ready
to become stars?
And I mean the biggest stars
the world has ever seen?
Honey, it's starting.
Oh, goodie.
On this
beautiful spring day of '27,
the world has never been
a better place.
The economy is forever booming
with no sign
of slowing down ever.
People have never been so happy,
and the future has never
looked so bright.
Meanwhile, over in Hollywood,
the new stars
of the silver screen
took the world by storm
and changed the face
of the motion picture
industry forever
with movies like The Good,
the Bad and the Stupids,
Look Behind You... And Then Down
and They Came from the Stars
to Hit You With a Frying Pan!
Part Four: Target Miami Beach.
The Minions have become
the kings of the box office,
and it seems like the public
just can't get enough of them.
We spent weeks with
the super-mini sensations,
and we're going to let you in
on a few of their secrets.
Our boys have moved into
a luxurious house
in Beverly Hills...
...where they'll be able
to enjoy
a comfortably large game room...
...and an equally comfortable
gigantic sauna.
Their lives have changed
- since fame hit them.
- Look, Minions!
They can't go anywhere
without being recognized.
Run, boys, run!
Looks are everything
in Tinseltown,
and the Minions are always
on the hunt
for the hottest,
most modern looks.
What trendsetters.
What fashion icons.
And not only that,
now there's Minions merchandise.
What will they think of next?
And boy, Hollywood has
never seen parties
like the ones those classy
gentlemen are throwing.
Yes, the Minions
are on top of the world.
They truly have it all.
Bank you, bank you.
Okay? Hah.
- Gooda, huh?
- Loving it.
...para aquí, eh?
Aquí.
- Wow.
- Incredible.
Eh, buh, buh, buh, buh. Sergei!
...película. Looka.
- Okay?
- On it.
Okay?
James, my boy,
you have a real gift
for filmmaking.
Ah, bank you.
Ja, you have what it takes
to become a director.
There could even be an Oscar
in your future.
O-Oscar?
Ah, it's an award given out to
the best films and filmmakers.
Ah...
And the Oscar for
the best movie ever goes to...
...James.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Bank you, bank you!
Eh...
Bank you!
- Bank you...
- James.
James?
Are you all right, my friend?
W-Wait, wh-what's-what's
happening? What is this?
I'll tell you what it is.
It's the future of cinema.
Everyone's doing it, Max.
From now on,
our movies are gonna have...
sound.
That right there, what
I just said, that was sound.
I have a very good feeling
about this.
Quiet, everyone.
Are you ready, Henry?
Ah, sí, sí, sí.
This will be great.
Okay, we're recording.
And action.
You disappear from my life
five years ago,
and now you think
you can come waltzing back in?
Well, no. No, I say!
Get lost, you handsome bastard.
Oh, Humphrey.
My mother warned me
about men like you.
Mm, baby,
piñata, carbonara,
lasagna.
What?
Was?
Stay with us, Sarge.
We need you.
What are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do?!
Yeah, Sarge?
Sí...
chihuahua!
Cut!
Chihuahua!
Oh, poop.
Cut!
Bikini.
- Can I
have a cup of coffee, please?
Tiny bit of milk.
Two sugars.
Thank you.
Balzac!
This is a disaster!
We've lost millions!
No.
- You know who I blame?
- Them!
Sadly, yes.
Get out of here!
But we wish you the best
of luck in your new endeavor,
and we hope
we can still be friends
- who never speak to each other.
- Leave.
And have a great life
away from us.
...Mbappé de Platini.
...Oscar.
O-Oscar?
James, you're never
going to win an Oscar.
You're done.
You're fired!
- Goodbye, Ridley.
- Goodbye, Max.
- Auf Wiedersehen, Eric.
- Bye-bye, Max.
- Hasta la vista, Quentin.
- Goodbye, Stephen.
- Tschüss!
- Ciao, Federico.
- Bye-bye, Max.
Dick.
Max.
Henry, James, good luck,
my friends.
Don't worry, boys.
It's just a minor setback.
Bank you.
You're going to be fine, James.
You're going to do great things.
Henry! James!
Bye-bye, Max.
No, no, no.
¿Por qué?
Ah...
Uh, okay.
Hey, Victor, bood night.
- Bood night, Peter.
- Hey, Nick, bood night.
- Ha, bood night, Greg.
- Bood night, George.
- Bood night, Stephen.
- Bood night, Bruno.
- Bood night, Julian.
- Thomas, bood night.
Bood night, James.
Hmm.
Huh?
Eu-Eureka.
Eureka!
Storya.
...Minions.
Bonanza...
Glory hallelujah!
Henry, come here, come here!
- Huh?
- ...storya!
- Looka, looka!
- Huh?
...movie.
Un movie de Minions.
Con monstras.
Sí, sí, sí!
¿Qué pasa?
Ah, looka, looka.
James...
...in la movies.
Movies?
...James.
Era fantástico.
Minions don't maka movies.
...Big Boss!
...y helpa James.
...Big Boss! Big Boss!
Oops.
Uh, scusa, Greg.
Uh, all is good?
Sí, sí.
...movies.
...Boss.
Big Boss!
- Big Boss! Big Boss!
- No, b-buddies.
Big Boss! Big Boss!
Big Boss!
Alles gut?
Come, Ed! ¡Vamos! ¡Vamos!
Ooh, there's romance.
How's that going to end up?
Whoo-hoo-hoo, he's so scary.
- James, I love your movie.
- Bank you.
Yes, it's clear
this is a real passion project,
and you need to make it,
whatever challenges
get in your way.
Sí, sí.
...advice.
Advice?
- Sí, sí. Bitte.
- Uh, well...
where do I start?
I mean, eh, uh, yeah.
Um, you guys have
film equipment?
Eh... no.
Ah, no film equipment. Uh-huh.
A crew?
Crew. No.
No crew either? Mm.
And you wrote a monster movie
with a very big monster?
Sí. ...kaiju.
And what are you going to use
for your monster?
Ah, uh...
Aha. Okay.
Listen to me carefully.
What I'm going to tell you is
very, very important.
So, if you want
to make a fantastisch,
very cool monster movie,
you will need a fantastisch,
very cool monster.
I can't really help you
with that, I'm afraid.
But I can give you this.
Un-un-un cámara.
Max, wirklich?
It was a gift from my father.
My first camera.
I'm passing it on to you now.
I believe in you, James.
I know you'll do great.
And remember,
a very cool monster movie
needs a very cool monster.
Max, darling. Come over here.
Good luck, guys.
...kaiju.
- Uh...
- Ed.
Oh...
- Hey, buddies, buddies.
- Sí.
Maka la movie!
Ed saved the day!
James is gonna get his monster!
Oh, well,
I'm happy you're happy.
Now do you mind if I go on
with the story?
Sorry, I get
a little excited sometimes.
Yes! Please continue.
What about Dick
and the other Minions?
Did they find a new boss?
Ooh, yes, well,
I was getting to it.
Dick and his friends were
about to fulfill the mission
of every Minion ever
and find their tribe
the greatest,
most evil master to serve.
Big Boss! Big Boss!
Attention.
Uh, attention, earthlings.
Cease current activities
and listen.
I am Dort,
and I was sent here
by the Supreme High Ruler
to judge this pathetic planet.
Big Boss?
But first, uh, Dort needs
to find loyal assistants.
Ooh, hey, you,
with the very cool spaceship.
Do you want to serve Dort?
Okay, let's go home.
You can do this kind of thing
on your mom's weekend.
Oh, yes, and...
Come on, please.
Leave me alone.
Guys, look at this winner.
Ah, thank you.
That's very kind.
Are you and your burly friends
interested in assisting Dort
in a potentially
dangerous mission?
Hey, I think the weirdo
in the lame robot suit
is talking to us.
Ha. I can assure you
that this is no costume.
Um, I mean...
You know, it's dangerous
to hang out here
dressed as a tin can.
Ah, ha-ha-ha. Ha, ha-ha-ha.
A tin can wishes it were
as tough as me, so there.
I sense you are
preparing a hostile attack.
Please stop.
Oh, yeah? Or what?
Whoa.
Why, you!
Now you've done it.
Dort was on a simple mission...
...to decide whether or not
Earth should be invaded,
and then you went and got all up
in Dort's
facial recognition sensors.
Dort has made his decision
regarding the fate
of this planet.
Dort is going to invade Earth
and enslave humanity!
Hey, hey, scusa, scusa.
Ah, greetings.
I am Dort.
Bello, Dort. Soy Dick.
Salutations, Richard.
Bah, no, no, no. Le Dick.
Mm, okay.
Do you want to assist Dort in
a potentially dangerous mission?
- Sí. Sí, sí! Yeah!
- Sí!
Great! Follow Dort back
to Dort's secret lair!
Big Boss!
MINIONS
Big Boss! Big Boss! Big Boss!
Okay.
- Henry?
- Sí, sí.
Ed? ¡Vamos!
Miso soup...
...yaki onigiri...
...edamame...
...daifuku!
Looka!
HENRY and JAMES:
Le kaiju!
Yes! Yes, I'm free!
F-F-Freedom.
Bah...
- Oh, happy day!
- Hmm?
Oh, I got to say, it is
so great to finally be out.
I have been trapped
in that book forever, and I...
...monstra.
- I am forever in your debt.
- Hmm.
And I just wanted to-- Whoa!
What you doing there, mister?
Whoo.
Oh, whoo, whoo, okay, okay.
Henry, no, no, no, no.
Oh, no, I feel like I've
disappointed you in some way.
I'm-I'm so sorry. Can I help?
...le monstras?
Monsters?
You want big, scary monsters?
Sí. Come here, come here.
Que para le movies.
Oh.
You need monsters
for your movie.
I know the perfect monsters
for you.
I'll take you to 'em.
Uh, uh, bank you!
Oh, by the way,
I'm Gary Orkam Oliver
Magma Ichabod the Deceiver.
But my friends just call me
Goomi for short.
Oh. Soy James.
Oh, James.
Rolls off the face tendrils.
James.
- ...Henry.
- Hey, bello.
Henry. Oh, I like it.
It sounds tough and rugged.
It's like,
"Oh, look out, here comes
Henry!"
...Ed.
Ed. Enchanté.
Oh, man,
it's gonna be so much fun!
Come on, come on!
- -HENRY: Huh?
- What a fantastic day!
No.
Wipe your insolent feet
before stepping into
the lair of Dort.
Uh...
...le lair?
Affirmative.
Everyone, file in.
Dort!
Where have you been?
Ah, Mrs. Konikoff.
Yes, so sorry.
Uh, Dort had
an important work meeting.
But I come with good news.
Look what I found
on my way back.
Those muffins you love.
I only like the blueberry ones!
Yes, you're in luck.
And I can only eat them
with a glass of...
Milk?
Enjoy your fruit-filled
baked goods.
What a sweet, sweet,
lovely woman.
She shall be spared
when Dort overthrows the planet.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
As will her cat.
Uh, hello. Sorry. Whoops.
Uh, everyone, commence greeting
Dort's roommate Floyd.
- Uh...
- Bello, Floyd.
Hey. Sup?
Mm, hey, Dort...
Whoa, whoa, lower
your throat volume, Minion.
This is definitely a lair.
No, looka.
Bink.
Bed.
Boyd.
No, no. Floyd.
Yeah, sí, Floyd.
You foolish, naive Minion.
You are actually standing in
a very futuristic
alien spaceship
made to look like
a dingy apartment.
Very realistic, isn't it?
Even the weird smell.
That's all fake.
Impressive, I know.
Huh? But, but...
But nothing!
No. Dort needs to retreat
to his private quarters
to, uh, report back
to his home planet.
Engaging in slamming mode!
Wow.
Oh, Dort is so cool!
Okay, okay. Calma, calma.
Hey, hey, buddies. Looka.
Wobble, wobble, wobble.
Wobble, wobble.
Fellas.
Wobble, wobble?
Wow, you're really
into your art, James.
You're so passionate.
I think you're a genius.
Oh, bank you.
Huh?
Ah.
Hey! Bello! Aw.
Ah la.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Eh?
Ah, phew.
Whoopsie.
Uh... Oh, oh, look!
There it is, our destination!
¡Vamos!
Let's go, fellas.
Uh, sí, sí.
...Dort.
Huh?
Attention.
Attention, Minions and Floyd.
Dort has finally
received his orders
from the Supreme High Ruler.
It is time
to officially invade Earth!
Yeah! Hey, Dort! Dort! Dort!
MINIONS
Dort! Dort!
DORT and MINIONS:
Dort! Dort! Dort! Dort!
Dort! Dort! Dort! Dort! Dort!
Dort!
What did I say about the noise?!
Oh! Oh, yes. Ooh, sorry.
My apologies.
With me. Dort. Dort.
Dort. Dort. Dort. Dort.
Attention, people of Earth!
Dort is officially
claiming your planet!
Yeah!
Oh. Well, hello there,
little fella.
Dort meant your sandcastle
no harm.
Hey.
Please stop your shovel attack.
Cease immediately,
or you will pay the price.
Looka, looka, buddies.
Let's see how you fare
against a similar attack,
tiny insurgent.
Hey, y-you in the robot suit.
No, no, no,
you can't kick that kid.
But he must be taught a lesson.
And also, he started it.
You are not from
around these parts, are you?
Well, no.
I originate
from the planet Metlar.
- Hmm?
- Near the G45T system?
Right.
I don't know where that is.
But I'm from a small town
in Minnesota myself,
so I understand the feeling
of being a stranger
in the big city.
So, what you're saying is
I am now free to kick him.
No, you can't.
Well, I should get a move on.
My friends and I are headed
to a protest for women's rights.
Do you believe
women and men are equal?
- Why, yes, of course.
- Oh, good.
In that you both now belong
to the Supreme Ruler equally.
You're so funny and cute.
Oh, I-I mean what you said.
What you said is cute.
Uh, pardon?
Come on, Debbie,
we're gonna be late.
Did you say Dort was...
SUFFRAGETTES
Give women the vote!
Bye! Don't kick children!
- Huh.
- Uh, Boss?
Minions, Dort is, uh, uh,
slightly postponing
Earth's invasion.
Huh?
You heard me. Follow Dort!
Give women the vote!
- Give women the vote!
- Uh.
Uh, buddies?
Bive women da bove!
Come on! Come on, come on!
James, you okay down there?
The entrance is straight ahead.
Patagonia!
I can't wait for you
to meet my friends!
Watch your step!
And here we are.
You're gonna love these gents.
We get them,
and then we go to...
- Ooh, ooh, Hollywood.
- Uh, Hollywood.
Yeah, sure-- to make your movie.
Whoa.
There they are!
Howard and Phillips.
Goomi, magnífico.
Right?
Ed, cinema. Cinema.
Don't be scared though.
They're such good guys.
Just try not to look
too delicious.
Huh?!
Hmm.
Mega kaiju!
Behold!
Hey, Goomi.
Thanks for the jailbreak.
All right, where were we?
Howard and Phillips
destroy world!
Yeah!
But wait, I'm sorry.
Quick question.
I want to eat one of these
funny-looking yellow guys first.
Is that okay?
Guys, guys.
We are not going
to destroy the world
nor eat anyone in this room.
Are we clear?
- Huh?
- Not really.
Destroying stuff
is-is kind of our thing.
Uh, not anymore, Phillips.
No, all that stuff is over.
We are no longer evil.
We work in
the motion picture industry.
See?
No worldwide destruction.
No devouring
funny-looking yellow guys.
We're just gonna help James here
make his dreams come true.
Huh?
Oh!
Okay.
Wink, wink.
Got it. All right, we're in.
They're in!
Come on, let's go to Hollywood!
Sí. Woot, woot!
Huh? Oh, no, no, no!
James, James.
...loco.
Le monstra bada.
Henry...
Stoppa, okay?
Stoppa.
C'est me movie, okay? Me movie!
Howard having super weird day.
Uh...
Faster!
Ah. Gooda, gooda.
Hey, Henry!
Mm!
Ah!
Mm-hmm.
Ooh, is this
where you make movies?
Sí.
Fantastic.
You hear that, guys?
This is where it all happens.
Come here!
Holy!
Wow, would you look at this!
Uh, uh.
- Uh...
- Oh! Oh, oh, oh, look.
- This is great.
- Huh?
Sí.
El a destructo la terra!
C'est besta storya.
Oh, James, you've painted
such a wonderful picture
with your beautiful gibberish.
Your movie
is gonna be fantastic.
Isn't it, guys?
Who cares about the movie?
I just want to eat people
and chase people and-and...
Smoosh people with feet!
Exactly. Smoosh.
Howard gets it.
Huh?
Okay, just a little
moment, please.
Uh, you and you, a word?
We'll be right back.
Oh. Okay.
Uh. Eh.
Goomi, what are we doing here?
Back in the good old days,
you were all about
going from planet to planet,
obliterating
everything in sight.
Now you want to make movies?
You've changed, man.
- Howard agree!
- Guys, guys, guys.
Where's the trust?
Of course we're gonna
destroy everything.
When those cameras
start rolling,
we're going to conjure Irene.
- Irene?!
- Irene?! Really?
Yes, Irene,
the eater of worlds herself.
We're gonna have our revenge,
but we're gonna destroy
everything on the planet.
Destroy!
- Howard, stop!
- Huh?
Uh... destroy?
Oh, hey, Henry, buddy.
James!
Get him!
Uh...
Ooh!
- Ow!
Hmm.
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Hey!
Eh, en garde!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Aha!
James!
Huh? Henry?
Henry?!
Oh, hide him. Hide him, quick.
Henry?
Oh, hi, James. Mm, no.
There's no Henry here.
Uh, just us monsters, you know,
talking about, uh...
uh, a friend of ours that would
be great in your movie.
This is Irene.
Oh.
Imagine the movie opens
with Irene being conjured.
The coolest monster ever,
unleashed upon
an unsuspecting world.
Oh, I promise you, James,
you've never seen
a monster like her.
Okay. ¡Vamos, vamos!
Hey, Ed, maka le movie.
GOOMI
Okay.
The big day has arrived.
And I have good news.
Last night, Henry and I were
having a little chat...
- Henry?
- Yeah, yeah, Henry.
And he said he's sorry
for being such a doink,
and also that the scene
we're about to do, you know,
when Irene arrives, he thinks
it's missing something.
- Huh?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
But Henry had a solution.
What if, when the monster
first comes out,
she eats a victim
to let the audience know
that she means business.
And better yet,
Henry has volunteered
to play the part
of the first sacrifice!
Henry! Bank you!
Mm-mm, mm-mm!
Oh, man, he seems excited, huh?
He's really getting
into the part. -Aw.
Well, James.
Jim. Jimmy.
Jimothy.
Are you ready to start making
your first movie?
Sí, sí.
By the way, are you okay with
me appearing in this scene?
Th-This is your project.
I don't want
to step on any toes.
No problemo. Lumiosa!
Sonos!
Y smoka!
Minions y Monstras.
Uno!
The end is finally here.
Earth is living
its last moments.
The monsters are back
with a vengeance!
The time for Irene
has come again!
Rahlia!
Yogsogoth!
Flitahgen!
Carbonica!
Alea Iacta Est!
Mercurio Sulubidis!
Cardamen Macchiato!
Welcome, the all-consuming,
all-powerful Irene!
Irene!
Wow, you're so beautiful!
So big, so orange, so...
G-G-Gooey!
Now feed, Irene!
Feast on our modest offering
and go forth into the world!
C'est gooda! Gooda, Henry!
James! Helpa me!
Huh? Helpa?
But por qué helpa?
James!
Uh, no, no!
Stoppa!
Irene, stoppa!
Bitte, bitte, stoppa!
Stop? I'm not gonna stop.
I've been waiting
for this moment for eons.
Irene is going to devour
everything and everyone.
No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Henry! Oh, oh, no!
Henry! Uh...
That was super fun.
What a perfect day
this has been.
Thank you so much.
Oh. Oh, no.
No, no. No. Thank you.
I really like you, Dort.
You're...
you're not like
the other men that I know.
Mm. You mean Dort is not
all about suppressing feelings
to avoid appearing vulnerable?
Well, yes, but more like,
with you...
well, I-I feel respected
and listened to.
Aw, Debbie.
Dort.
C'est la Henry!
Dort! Kawasaki le kaiju!
Help buddy, buddy.
- Huh?
- Oh, my heavens!
Look at that thing!
Well, he's no match
for my robot boyfriend.
Go! Get him, baby!
Um, yes, yes.
But that thing i-is huge!
Uh, I, um...
Okay.
- Dort?
- Dort!
- Uh, uh...
- Hmm?
Buddies.
...Dort.
Y tú. Helpa Henry!
Huh? Helpa Henry?
Sí, helpa Henry!
Buddies!
Helpa Henry!
On my command, prepare to fire!
And, uh...
Fall back! Fall back!
Huh?
- Uh.
- Ooh. Uh.
Uh, uh, uh, uh...
Hmph.
Meow.
Wait, wait, wait! Slow down!
Dort!
Where are we going?
Opena!
Huh?
Phew.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Ouch! Ouch!
- Get out of here, you weirdo.
- Ouch!
Henry.
So I guess this is the end.
Irene, finish him!
Huh?
Oh!
No, no, no, no, no!
Henry!
Huh?
Ah, no!
Ah...
Huh? Henry!
James!
Toot, toot!
- Minions!
- Huh?
What?
Mm, piñata!
Huh?
Pow! Pow! Pow! Pow!
Click! Click! Click?
Yah! Yah!
Ow!
Bazooka!
James!
Looka, looka!
Go, go, go!
Oh...!
Good game, fellas,
but it's over.
Irene, take 'em all down!
Uh, James.
Huh?
Ah, ah, what's happening?
Who dares?
I am Dort!
Bravo!
Call off your attack, or else.
Oh, yeah? Or else, what?
We've got Irene!
Agreed.
But I've got...
Minions!
Piñata!
Uh, no.
Ah...
Kanpai!
Pew, pew, pew, pew, pew,
pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew!
GOOMI
Irene!
Hey, Goomi!
Huh?
- Huh?
- Oh, no.
No, no. No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no!
Undo la spella.
Command-Zed!
Run for it, boys!
Undo!
Command-Zed!
Don't you dare lock me
in there again, or I'm gonna...
Dick!
Tú le besta.
No, Greg. Tú le besta.
Ah. Oh!
Oh.
Dort! Dort!
Oh, Debbie!
Yes, indeed.
The day and Earth itself
was saved.
All was right in the world.
And get this.
Ed had never stopped filming.
And so,
after months of hard work,
and with the help
of all of his buddies,
James had made his dream
come true.
He had done it.
He had finally made his movie.
And let me tell you,
watching the movie play
with a theater full of people,
there was truly nothing better.
James! James!
James! James! James!
Bank you. Bank you a tutti.
Bank you.
Bravo!
I'm so proud of you, James!
Oh, xiè xie.
Fantastic work, Minions.
That was incredible.
Fun for the whole family.
And the evening just
kept getting better and better.
Uh...
Uh.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Bank you, Henry.
Oh, was it
a glorious, beautiful moment
that none of them
would ever forget.
They had done it.
The Minions had achieved success
in the face of adversity.
And even though
it took a long time
and it wasn't always easy,
they came out on top.
As a group.
As a tribe.
As friends.
Aw!
Cut!
The movie is finito!
Bank you, toda!
Bank you!
Hey, hey.
- Bank you!
- Way to go, Minions.
Ooh, hey! ¡Cuidado! ¡Cuidado!
Hey!
Thank you.
Whoo!
- Hey.
- Come here, come here.
Bank you, Floyd!
Aw.
Eh, James, tapioca?
- Tapioca.
- Credits!
Ooh.
Eh.
Hey, hey, Mini Boss.
Whoa!
Bello?
Stuart, helpa con la booka.
Uh...
Ah, uh, uh...
Ow! Ow! Ooh!
Stop! Hey, stop it!
Eh?
Uh...
Ah.
Ooh, looka, looka!
Come here, come here!
...Kitty Gru!
Rawr.
...Sheepy Gru!
Baa...
Ooh, ooh.
...Penguin Gru!
...Piggy Gru!